{"Topic": "Oceans and Seas", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Tides in the sea are caused by", "op1": "Effects of the moon", "op2": "Effects of the sun", "op3": "Sun and the moon", "op4": "Gravitational centrifugal or centripetal forces", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following oceans is between Africa and Australia?", "op1": "Indian Ocean", "op2": "Arctic Ocean", "op3": "South Atlantic Ocean", "op4": "South Pacific Ocean", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The canal joining Baltic Sea to North Sea is", "op1": "Neil Canal", "op2": "Kiel Canal", "op3": "Panama Canal", "op4": "Suez Canal", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the smallest ocean of the world?", "op1": "Pacific", "op2": "Indian", "op3": "Atlantic", "op4": "Arctic", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Through which one of the following Straits, does a tunnel connect the United Kingdom and France?", "op1": "Davis Strait", "op2": "Denmark Strait", "op3": "Strait of Dover", "op4": "Strait of Gibraltar", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which one of the following countries is planning to construct a rival to the Panama Canal to link the Pacific and Atlantic Oceans?", "op1": "Colombia", "op2": "Costa Rica", "op3": "Guatemala", "op4": "Nicaragua", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Sargasso Sea is a part of :", "op1": "North Atlantic ocean", "op2": "South Atlantic Ocean", "op3": "North Pacific Ocean", "op4": "North Sea", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The Suez Canal connects -", "op1": "Mediterranean and Red Seas", "op2": "Baltic and Caspian Seas", "op3": "Mediterranean and North Seas", "op4": "Red Sea and Caspian Sea", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The sea bed sloping gradually and bordering the continent is known as -", "op1": "Coast", "op2": "Continental Shelf", "op3": "Continental Platform", "op4": "Continental slope", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The oceans cover ______ of the surface of the earth.", "op1": "50%", "op2": "60%", "op3": "71%", "op4": "80%", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Bosphorus Strait links :", "op1": "Black Sea and Adriatic Sea", "op2": "Mediterranean and Adriatic Sea", "op3": "Sea of Marmara and Black Sea", "op4": "North Sea and Baltic Sea", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following countries does not have a coastline with Arabian Sea?", "op1": "Afghanistan", "op2": "Pakistan", "op3": "Oman", "op4": "Iran", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Suez Canal was nationalized in the year :", "op1": "1954", "op2": "1955", "op3": "1956", "op4": "1957", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The land near which of the following is considered the lowest point on land on earth?", "op1": "Caspian Sea", "op2": "Dead Sea", "op3": "Black Sea", "op4": "Salton Sea", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Where is the deepest part of world's ocean located?", "op1": "Arctic Ocean", "op2": "Atlantic Ocean", "op3": "Indian Ocean", "op4": "Pacific Ocean", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following oceans has the most coral reefs?", "op1": "Arctic Ocean", "op2": "Atlantic Ocean", "op3": "Pacific Ocean", "op4": "Indian Ocean", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following oceans holds almost 50% of total water on the planet?", "op1": "Pacific Ocean", "op2": "Atlantic Ocean", "op3": "Indian Ocean", "op4": "Arctic Ocean", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Match the seas with the coastal countries?", "op1": "1 - C; 2 - D; 3 - A; 4 - B", "op2": "1 - D; 2 - C; 3 - A; 4 - B", "op3": "1 - D; 2 - C; 3 - B; 4 - A", "op4": "1 - D; 2 - A; 3 - C; 4 - B", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following oceans has the most trenches or deeps?", "op1": "Atlantic Ocean", "op2": "Indian Ocean", "op3": "Arctic Ocean", "op4": "Pacific Ocean", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "A shallow body of water protected from a larger body of water (usually the ocean) by sandbars, barrier islands, or coral reefs is called -", "op1": "Strait", "op2": "Gulf", "op3": "Lagoon", "op4": "Bay", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The much-in-news Guantanamo Bay is located in which of the following countries?", "op1": "Mexico", "op2": "Cuba", "op3": "Guatemala", "op4": "Nicaragua", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which country has the longest coastline in the world?", "op1": "Canada", "op2": "Russia", "op3": "U.S.A.", "op4": "Indonesia", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which is the largest gulf in the world?", "op1": "Gulf of Thailand", "op2": "Gulf of Oman", "op3": "Gulf of Alaska", "op4": "Gulf of Mexico", "Answer": 2}]}